Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites
2017-ongoing
Fales Library and Special Collections
New York University. Libraries. Avery Fisher Center
MSS.496
238 websites
This collection consists of a selection of websites produced and operated by contemporary composers for the promotion of their work and careers. "Contemporary" we define as living or, in a few cases, very recently deceased. "Composers" we define as creative musicians who are working within, are descending from, or are in some significant way connected to the Western traditions of concert music; this includes composers who produce notated scores plus those whose work embraces improvisation, collaborative composition, and other post-modern/post- classical creative practices. The curatorial emphasis is on young, emerging American composers. Their sites typically include biographical data, calendars of performances, catalogs of scores and recordings, and embedded audio and video. Capture of the sites began in 2014 and is ongoing.
Box electronic records
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information. If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials. If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to fales.library@nyu.edu. Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Conditions Governing Access
Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions.
Custodial History
Websites are selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Accruals
Websites are crawled quarterly, semiannually, annually, or just once, as noted in the appraisal note attached to each site instance.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in alphabetical order by last name of the composer.
Web sites.; Composers -- 21st century
- Adamo, Mark, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Scope and Contents
  The website contains descriptions of his compositions, which include chamber and choral pieces as well as operas. It also has a biography of the artist, links to reviews of his works, examples of prose pieces written by Adamo, and information about which of his works are currently in print. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
  Accruals
  Site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://markadamo.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Adler, Christopher, February 2015- ongoing; cuid5909; 4 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.christopheradler.com and adlerforum.blogspot.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  adlerforum.blogspot.com, an external site, was included due to its contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl.
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  The website contains a biography of Adler, a list of his compositions with PDF files of descriptions of the works, a calendar of his events, information about his projects, a list of his recordings and writings, as well as reviews of him and his works. His compositions draw on the traditional music of Laos and Thailand as well as his interest in mathematics to form cross-cultural hybrid concert pieces. He is best known for his work with the khaen, a traditional instrument from southeast Asia. Soundcloud audio files were not captured due to technological constraints. Capture of site began in August 2016. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Aftab, Arooj, August 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://aroojaftab.bandcamp.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Bandcamp audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains information about her compositions and projects, a discography of her published albums, and examples of her works in the form of embedded audio files. The compositions featured on the site highlight her work as a composer of classically inspired yet experimental acoustic and electronic ambient music. Capture of the site began in August 2015. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Akiho, Andy, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5897; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.andyakiho.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Parts of the live site involving Youtube were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a calendar of his events, 15 image files of Akiho, 34 audio files recording his compositions, a catalog of his albums, and a list of his scores. Embedded video files were not captured due to technological constraints. Akiho's works fall in the genre of contemporary classical music. Capture of site began in February 2014. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Aldridge, Robert, August 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  The website contains descriptions of his compositions, which consist mainly of instrumental pieces for orchestra, opera and classical ensembles, a biography of the artist, a discography of his published works, links to reviews of his works, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files. Capture of the site began in August 2015. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.robertlivingstonaldridge.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Alexander, Elizabeth, April 2014-ongoing; 1 websites in one archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of seafarerpress.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains the music of Elizabeth Alexander, a composer that focuses on orchestral, chamber, piano and vocal works, often liturgical in nature. It includes sheet music for purchase, reviews, commissions, biographies of the composer, a complete catalog of her works, videos of performances of her works, and journal entries. The website was initially captured under the URL http://elizabethalexander.com/ until 2018, when it redirected to https://www.seafarerpress.com/.
- Alexander, Kathryn, August 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  The website contains descriptions of her compositions, which consist mainly of instrumental pieces for traditional and technological instruments for ensembles, a biography of the artist, lists of her recognitions, talks, and prose writings, a calendar of her events, and a catalog of her musical works with embedded audio examples. Capture of the site began in August 2015. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.kathrynalexander.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded audio was broken in the live site as well as the site capture.
- Alves, Bill, February 2015- ongoing; cuid5908; 3 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of www.billalves.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his compositions, a catalog of his albums, a bibliography of Alves' writings, and reviews of his works. Soundcloud audio files were not captured due to technological constraints. Alves' musical works are composed for traditional acoustic instruments from around the world as well as electronic media. Capture of site began in February 2015. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Ames, Charles, May 2014- ongoing; cuid5857; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://charlesames.net/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of Ames, a list of his works, descriptions of how he makes his music, and links to his publications. Ames' uses his background in mathematics and programming to make music using computers and traditional instruments. Capture of the site began in December 2016. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Amram, David, August 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  The website contains descriptions of his compositions, which include chamber, orchestral, and choral pieces as well as operas. It also has a biography of the artist, links to reviews of his works, a calendar of Amram's events, and links to videos of performances of his works. Capture of the site began in August 2015. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://david-amram.blogspot.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Anderson, Laurie, August 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.laurieanderson.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Flash video files on the site were not captured due to technological constraints.
  This accession consists of the archived website of composer Laurie Anderson. The website contains information about her compositions and projects, a gallery of images and videos featuring her works, and a calendar of her events. The compositions featured on the site highlight her work as a violinist and composer of experimental electronic music. She also performs as a rock musician. Capture of the site began in August 2015. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Andres, Timo, May 2014- ongoing; cuid5876; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.andres.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a list of his musical works, a biography of the artist, a calendar of his events, images of the artist, a discography of his published pieces, and links to reviews of Andres and his works. Many of Andres' compositions involve the piano, and his works are mainly orchestral or chamber music. Capture of the site began in August 2016. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Applebaum, Mark, August 2015- ongoing; cuid5934; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.markapplebaum.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his works and a discography of his published albums, images of the artist, a calendar of his events, and his CV. Best known as a jazz pianist, he has also composed works in the genres of chamber, orchestral, and electro-acoustic music. Capture of the website began in August 2016. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
- Appleton, Jon, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5939; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.appletonjon.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his works, recordings, and prose publications, images of Appleton, and examples of his musical compositions in the form of embedded audio and video files. Appleton composes instrumental, choral, and electro-acoustic music, although he is best known for the latter. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Ariza, Christopher, August 2015- ongoing; cuid5937; 3 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.flexatone.org/article/christopherAriza in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, his CV, a list of his musical works and prose publications, and examples of his musical compositions in the form of embedded audio files. Ariza's music combines his background in programming and design with contemporary music theory to create works that blend technology with more traditional instruments. Capture of the site began in August 2015. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Baker, Tom, February 2015-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Tom Baker is a composer, guitarist, improviser, and electronic musician who is in Seattle new-music scene. The website contains a calendar, compositions, guitar pieces and improvisations, CD recordings, his projects, press and reviews, and a blog.
  Website is accrued annually.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of tombakermusic.com and tombakercomposer.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Banks, Rusty, August 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.rustybanks.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, examples of his work in the form of embedded video files, and a list of his compositions. The music on the site is mainly acoustic, featuring pieces using traditional instruments for ballet and orchestra as well as more modern multimedia compositions. Capture of the site began in August 2015. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
- Barros, Bernardo, July 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Barros is an improvisational musician and composer who creates works with acoustic and electronic instruments. The website details Barros' works and contains a calendar of the artist's events, information about his compositions, and links to his Soundcloud and BabelScores pages. Capture of the site began in July 2017. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
  New site crawls are accrued annually.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://bernardobarros.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  https://www.babelscores.com/es/BernardoBarros, an external site, was included due to its contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl.
  Parts of the live site involving Soundcloud were not captured due to technological constraints.
- Basinski, William, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5883; 2 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.mmlxii.com/ and https://soundcloud.com/william-basinski in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Some external sites were included due to their contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl. This site is https://soundcloud.com/william-basinski.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a calendar of his events, a catalog of his albums, 32 audio files recording his musical works, and 1 video file recording a performance of one of his compositions. Basinski makes use of obsolete technologies as well as modern ones to create his compositions. Capture of website began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Bates, Mason, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.masonbates.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Works pages on the site were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a calendar of his events, press relating to Bates and his works, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a DJ and composer of music that integrates electronic music with classical and opera. Capture of the site began in April 2014. This description is based on the January 2018 capture of the site.
- Beck, Jeremy, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5864; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.beckmusic.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of Beck, PDF files of his prose writings and listing his compositions, 30 embedded video files recording performances of his works, and reviews of him and his music. His works encompass opera and contemporary music with strong classical influences. Capture of site began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Beeferman, Gordon, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.gordonbeeferman.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Soundcloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, press relating to him and his works, a calendar of his events, and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a pianist and composer of opera, jazz, chamber, and orchestra music, making use of improvisation as well as scored pieces. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Behrman, David, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5849; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.dbehrman.net/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, lists of his musical works arranged by decade, 21 audio files recording his compositions, 1 video file recording a performance of one of his works, 5 image files of the artist, and information on his past projects and collaborations. Behrman composes sound and multimedia installations for performance in gallery spaces as well as more traditional music pieces meant to be played in concerts. Most of his pieces are flexible in their composition and rely on electronic media and performer interaction. Capture of site began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Bernofsky, Lauren, May 2014- ongoing; cuid5853; 2 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of www.laurenbernofsky.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of her works, a discography of her published albums, and a calendar of her events. Bernofsky has composed choral, chamber, and orchestral works for films, musicals, operas, and ballets, as well as concerts. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Betinis, Abbie, May 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.abbiebetinis.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  New site crawls are accrued quarterly.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of her compositions, a calendar of her events, examples of her works in the form of embedded audio files and prose pieces, her resume, photos of the artist, and reviews of Betinis' compositions. The music featured on the site uses traditional and electro-acoustic instruments as well as vocalists. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Bettison, Oscar, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.oscarbettison.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.